<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jan Wynen</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jan Wynen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing and explaining the effects of organizational autonomy in the public sector. (FWO PhD project June 2011- May 2014)</title>
      <link>/project/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/phd/</guid>
      <description>In the last three decades, public tasks have been shifted from central government to a proliferated periphery of autonomous agencies. According to the New Public Management (NPM) doctrine, organizational autonomy would induce these agencies to develop a more private sector-like management, to be more customer-oriented, and to be more accountable for results. Although many governments of most OECD countries continue(d) to change the structure of their public sector fundamentally, following NPM and post-NPM recipes, little was known of the effect of increased autonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How history matters for public sector organizations: examining the effect of past changes on organizational autonomy (FWO postdoctoral research project 2015-2018)</title>
      <link>/project/fwo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/fwo/</guid>
      <description>In response to economic pressures and increasing demands on public sector performance, subsequent waves of public sector reforms were introduced over the last decades (Pollitt &amp;amp; Bouckaert, 2011). During these reform waves, public sector organizations were subject to a wide array of structural changes such as: giving up and re-integrating tasks, the absorption of (parts of) other organizations, the secession of parts to other organizations and changes in legal status. Research has largely neglected the impact of such sequential and repeated structural changes on public sector organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reform stress in the public sector: does the constant exposure to anti-bureaucratic reforms paradoxically undermine the entrepreneurial nature of public sector organizations? (VENI research project 2018-2021)</title>
      <link>/project/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>In response to economic pressures and increasing demands on public sector performance, subsequent waves of public sector reforms were introduced over the last decades. During these reform waves, public sector organizations were subject to a wide array of structural changes happening in rapid succession. While there is little consistency in these reforms, a strong focus on creating entrepreneurial, non-bureaucratic organizations is one tenet all reforms share. Yet literature warns for reform fatigue and reform stress within organizations, suggesting that such a constant exposure to structural changes may in fact undermine the anti-bureaucracy objective of reforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow-healing wounds? How continuous structural reforms in the public sector reduce levels of job satisfaction and slow the recovery of job satisfaction in the long term. (FWO project international co-applicant together with Koen Verhoest (main applicant)</title>
      <link>/project/fwo3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/fwo3/</guid>
      <description>In the last decades, waves of structural reforms have been implemented in OECD countries to create more efficient public services, causing some organizations to have experienced severe and continuous trajectories of for instance mergers, splits and changes in legal form. While governments continuously impose structural reforms to improve public sector performance, we may simultaneously expect such continuous structural reforms to have detrimental side-effects, such as strong reductions in employee job satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable or turbulent organizational reform histories in the public sector: causes and effects? (UA BOF project 2015-2019)</title>
      <link>/project/bof/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bof/</guid>
      <description>This PhD project is supervised by me and prof. dr. Koen Verhoest. It is funded by the University of Antwerp and executed by Bjorn Kleizen. Bjorn studies through quantitative and qualitative research the impact of reforms on the organizational climate in public sector organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Twitter as a public communication strategy: Can 140 characters reduce the Performance-Satisfaction Gap in the public sector? (FWO project international co-applicant together with Koen Verhoest (main applicant) and Wouter van Dooren 2019-2013)</title>
      <link>/project/fwo2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/fwo2/</guid>
      <description>Customer satisfaction regarding public services is often only loosely coupled to changes in actual performance. This gap between satisfaction and performance may lead to misguided reforms and may erode trust in public services. Literature shows how the incapacity of customers to assess actual performance can be attributed to the bounded rationality of customers. We know less about how public communication influences this bounded decision making that underlies the performance-satisfaction gap. With the rise of social media, the communication channels for public sector organizations have grown extensively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>